nordson.com 2019-02-01

# General Privacy Policy | Nordson Corporation

**1\. Our commitment to protecting your privacy.**  
Your privacy is important to Nordson.  We’ve developed this General Privacy Policy to address how Nordson, its subsidiaries and affiliates worldwide collect, use, disclose, transfer and store your information.  To ensure that your personal data is secure, we communicate our information security and privacy guidelines to all Nordson employees and enforce privacy safeguards within the company.

For personal information received from the European Economic Area (EEA) and/or Switzerland, see Section 10 of this General Privacy Policy.

**2\. What information do we collect?  **  
For visitors to our publicly available website, we collect information from you when you browse or register on our site, place an order, subscribe to our newsletter, respond to a survey or fill out a form.  When ordering or registering on our site, as appropriate, you may be asked to enter your name, e-mail address, mailing address and/or phone number. We also collect certain information about your session which does not identify individual users when you visit our website, including internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider, referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp and clickstream data. We also use cookies as described in Section 5 below. Please note that this online General Privacy Policy applies only to information collected through our website and not to information collected offline.  
For employees of Nordson, we collect various types of data about you that is needed for your working relationship with the company as well as organizational planning and management.

**3\. What do we use web visitor’s information for?**  
We collect personal data for legitimate business purposes, which may include:   
·         To personalize your experience (your information helps us to better respond to your individual needs)  
·         To improve our website (we continually strive to improve our website offerings based on the information and feedback we receive from you)  
·         To improve customer service (your information helps us to more effectively respond to your customer service requests and support needs)  
·         To process transactions  
·         To administer a contest, promotion, survey or other site feature  
·         To send periodic emails (the email address you provide may be used to send you information, respond to inquiries, and/or other requests or questions)  
·         To meet government, national security, public interest, or law enforcement requirements  
·         In an emergency where the health or security of an individual may be endangered  
·         Other purposes disclosed at the time of collection or otherwise compatible with the above, the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework, and the Swiss – U.S. Privacy Shield Framework

**4\. How do we protect your information?  **  
We implement a variety of security measures to maintain the safety of your personal information when you place an order or enter, submit, or access your personal information.  These precautions may include password protections for online information systems and restricted access to personal data.    
All inquiries from outside the company concerning identity, employment record, or performance of a current or terminated employee are referred to the Human Resources department and/or an attorney in the Law Department, who will verify the credentials of the agency representative before releasing information about a current or terminated employee.    
Nordson takes reasonable and appropriate measures to secure your personal data.  

Our publicly available website is hosted on a secure server.

**5\. Do we use cookies?  **  
Yes. Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer’s hard drive through your Web browser (if you allow) that enables the sites’ or service providers’ systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information.  Our Cookie Notice has been revised to conform to GDPR standards and provides information on the cookies we apply.

We use cookies to help us remember and process the items in your shopping cart, understand and save your preferences for future visits and gather information about site traffic and site interaction so that we can offer better site experiences and tools to our online visitors in the future. We may contract with third-party service providers to assist us in better understanding our site visitors. These service providers are not permitted to use the information collected on our behalf except to help us conduct and improve our business.

**6\. Do we disclose any information to outside parties?**  
We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer information to outside parties.  This excludes third parties who assist us with human capital management, employee equity compensation, in operating our website, conducting our business, or servicing you, so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential.  We may also release your information when we believe release is necessary to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect our or other’s rights, property, or safety, or share personal information as necessary to other corporate entities as part of a business transition such as a merger, acquisition, or sale of assets.

  However, non-personally identifiable visitor information may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses.  Because we value your privacy, we have taken the necessary precautions to be in compliance with the California Online Privacy Protection Act.  We will not distribute your personal information to outside parties without your consent.

**7\. Choice, Data Integrity & Access**  
Nordson takes reasonable steps to ensure that personal data is accurate, complete and current.  

For our employees. Nordson provides individuals the opportunity to opt out from allowing the company to disclose his or her personal information to a third party or to use it for any purpose. Nordson reserves the right to maintain any personal information that it is required to keep or maintain for compliance purposes or to protect itself or preserve its legal rights under pending, threatened or potential legal action.  Certain Nordson employees who are in the Workday human capital management system may review and correct his or her data at any time.  All employees are asked to inform the Human Resources or Payroll departments, or his or her manager, immediately in the event of changes in personal information.  If any information is inaccurate or incomplete, the individual may request that inaccurate information be corrected.

**8\. Collection of Personal Information from Children  **  
We do not collect any information from anyone under 13 years of age.  Our website, products and services are all directed to people who are at least 13 years old or older.

**9\. Changes to our General Privacy Policy**  
Nordson conducts an annual self-assessment in order to verify that this General Privacy Policy is published and implemented within the Company and that it conforms to the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework, and Swiss – U.S. Privacy Shield Framework.  If we decide to change our General Privacy Policy, we will post those changes on this page, and/or update the General Privacy Policy modification date below.   

**10.   EU-U.S. Privacy Shield and Swiss – U.S. Privacy Shield**  
For details on how we process the personal data of website visitors from the EEA and Switzerland, please see Nordson’s Privacy Notice for European Economic Area Visitors to Nordson’s Website (“EU Privacy Policy”) and Nordson’s Privacy Shield Policy for European Economic Area and Switzerland Visitors to Nordson’s Website (“Privacy Shield Policy”) as set out in Annex A to this General Privacy Policy below. Our EU Privacy Policy applies to the way we collect and process personal data that is covered by the EU General Data Protection Regulation. The EU Privacy Policy and Privacy Shield Policy will prevail to the extent of any inconsistency with this General Privacy Policy.  

For details on how we process the personal data of our employees in the EEA and Switzerland, please see Nordson’s Privacy Shield Policy for European Economic Area and Switzerland Employees (“Employee Privacy Shield Policy”). The Employee Privacy Shield Policy is made available to employees in the European Economic Area and Switzerland through effective communications channels, including on Nordson’s corporate intranet and from Nordson Human Resources Managers and Data Protection Officers covering our EEA and Swiss office locations. The Employee Privacy Shield Policy will prevail to the extent of any inconsistency with this General Privacy Policy.

**11\. Inquiries/Contact Us**  
Nordson commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information. Individuals may contact Gina Beredo, Deputy General Counsel & Assistant Secretary, at:  [nordson.privacy@nordson.com](mailto:nordson.privacy@nordson.com). 

Date: 23 May 2018

**Annex A  
Privacy Shield Policy for European Economic Area and Swiss Visitors to Nordson’s Website**

**A. Definitions**

"Controller" means a person or organization which, alone or jointly with others, determines the purposes and means of the Processing of EU Personal Data.

"EU Personal Data" for the purposes of this Privacy Shield Policy means all data about an identified or identifiable individual visitor to Nordson’s website that are within the scope of Directive 95/46/EC, or equivalent law currently in effect in the EU or Switzerland, which are received by the Company from the European Economic Area and/or Switzerland for Processing, and are recorded in any form.

"General Privacy Policy" means the privacy policy that applies generally to all visitors to Nordson’s website, wherever located.

"Nordson" or "Company" means Nordson Corporation and all of its subsidiaries worldwide.

"Nordson U.S." means Nordson Corporation and its U.S. subsidiaries.

"Privacy Shield" means the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as agreed between the European Commission and the U.S. Department of Commerce, which came into effect on July 12, 2016.

"Privacy Shield Policy" means the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as agreed between the European Commission and the U.S. Department of Commerce, which came into effect on July 12, 2016 and the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as agreed between the Swiss Federal Data Protection and Information Commissioner the U.S. Department of Commerce, which came into effect on April 12, 2017..

"Processing" of EU Personal Data means any operation or set of operations which is performed upon EU Personal Data, whether or not by automated means, such as collection, recording, organization, storage, adaptation or alteration, retrieval, consultation, use, disclosure or dissemination, and erasure or destruction. "Process", "Processing" and "Processed" shall be construed accordingly.

**B. Scope & Application**

Nordson U.S. commits to subject to the Privacy Shield Principles and the Supplemental Principles (collectively, the "Principles" and each a "Principle") all EU Personal Data received in reliance on the Privacy Shield.

The controlled U.S. subsidiaries of Nordson U.S., as identified in the Nordson Corporation self-certification listing available [here](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000TOT2AAO&status=Active), also adhere to the Privacy Shield Principles.

This Privacy Shield Policy supplements the General Privacy Policy and applies to you if you are an EEA and/or Swiss visitor to Nordson’s publicly available website. Where this Privacy Shield Policy is inconsistent with the General Privacy Policy with regard to the Processing of EU Personal Data, this Privacy Shield Policy will prevail.

**C. Compliance with EU-U.S. and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework**

Nordson U.S. complies with the Privacy Shield regarding the collection, use, and retention of EU Personal Data transferred from the European Economic Area and Switzerland to the United States. Nordson U.S. has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Principles, including the Principles of: 

  * Notice;
  * Choice;
  * Accountability for Onward Transfer;
  * Security;
  * Data Integrity and Purpose Limitation;
  * Access; and
  * Recourse, Enforcement and Liability.

If there is any conflict between the terms in this Privacy Shield Policy and the Principles, the Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification, please visit <https://www.privacyshield.gov/>.

**1\. Notice**

Nordson U.S. adheres to the Notice Principle with regard to all EU Personal Data received in reliance on the Privacy Shield. 

  1. **What EU Personal Data do we collect?**  
When you visit our publicly available website, Nordson U.S. collects and Processes the types of personal information described in section 2 of the General Privacy Policy.
  2. **What do we use your EU Personal Data for?**  
We collect your EU Personal Data for a range of legitimate business purposes described in section 3 of the General Privacy Policy.
  3. **Who do we disclose your EU Personal Data to?**  
Nordson U.S. does not disclose your EU Personal Data to third parties except as described in section 6 of the General Privacy Policy. Further, Nordson may transfer your EU Personal Data if the Company sells or transfers all or a portion of its business or assets (for example, in the event of a merger or reorganization, joint venture or liquidation).

Nordson U.S. may be required to disclose EU Personal Data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

Your EU Personal Data may be Processed and stored in the U.S. and other countries where Nordson’s affiliates, subsidiaries or agents are located. Nordson utilizes a range of methods to transfer EU Personal Data across country borders. These methods include consent, contractual methods, and/or regulatory authority certifications.

**2\. Choice**

Nordson U.S. adheres to the Choice Principle and the Choice – Timing of Opt Out Supplemental Principle.

You have the opportunity to choose (opt out) from: (1) the disclosure of your EU Personal Data to a third party (other than Nordson U.S. agents doing work on our instructions); and (2) the use of your EU Personal Data for a purpose materially different to that for which the data was originally collected (as set forth in the General Privacy Policy or this Privacy Shield Policy, or subsequently authorized by you). You may opt out by contacting us using the Nordson Contact Details provided in Section 7 below.

**3\. Accountability for Onward Transfer of EU Personal Data**

Nordson U.S. adheres to the Accountability for Onward Transfer Principle and the Obligatory Contracts for Onward Transfer Supplemental Principle.

Nordson U.S. shares EU Personal Data with third-party suppliers based on contractual arrangements which, among other things, ensure that the Principles are respected as required, that the third-party supplier acts only on its instructions and that the data are appropriately secured by the third-party supplier.

In the context of onward transfers, Nordson U.S. is responsible for the Processing of the EU Personal Data it receives and subsequently transfers to a third-party agent acting on its behalf. Nordson remains liable under the Principles if its agent Processes such EU Personal Data in a manner inconsistent with the Principles, unless Nordson proves that it is not responsible for the event giving rise to the damage.

Please also see Section 2 above relating to Choice.

**4\. Security**

Nordson U.S. adheres to the Security Principle.

Nordson U.S. takes reasonable and appropriate measures to protect EU Personal Data from loss, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration and destruction, taking into account the risks involved in the Processing and the nature of the EU Personal Data. For additional information on the data security measures employed by Nordson, please see section 4 of the General Privacy Policy.

**5\. Data Integrity and Purpose Limitation**

Nordson U.S. adheres to the Data Integrity and Purpose Limitation Principle.

Nordson's collection and Processing of EU Personal Data is limited to the purposes for which it was collected as set forth in section 3 of the General Privacy Policy, unless further use has been subsequently authorized by you. Nordson may also Process EU Personal Data for compliance with our legal obligations, internal and external auditing and due diligence, security and fraud prevention, preserving or defending Nordson’s legal rights.

Nordson takes reasonable steps to ensure that the EU Personal Data it holds is accurate, complete and current. We rely on you to update and correct your EU Personal Data, where necessary. If you wish to make a request to update or correct your EU Personal Data, please use the Nordson Contact Details provided in Section 7 below.

Where Nordson U.S. is acting as a data Controller, Nordson may retain EU Personal Data as long as necessary for the Company to: (a) complete the purpose for which it was collected; (b) meet any applicable legal requirements; or (c) protect its legitimate interests, including with respect to actual or potential legal claims.

**6\. Access**

Nordson U.S. adheres to the Access Principle and Access Supplemental Principle.

You may obtain access to EU Personal Data that Nordson holds which is relevant to you. You may also correct, amend or delete that information where it is inaccurate, or has been Processed in violation of the Principles. If you wish to request access to your EU Personal Data, please use the Nordson Contact Details provided in Section 7 below.

Nordson may limit or deny access as provided in the Principles, including where: (a) the rights of persons other than the requesting individual would be violated; or (b) the burden or expense of providing access would be disproportionate to the risks to the individual’s privacy in the case in question.

**7\. Nordson Contact Details**

In compliance with the Principles, Nordson U.S. commits to resolve complaints about our collection or use of your EU Personal Data. If you have queries or complaints about this Privacy Shield Policy or wish to exercise your rights under Sections 2, 5, 6 or 8, you should first contact Nordson by: 

  * email at: [nordson.privacy@nordson.com](mailto:nordson.privacy@nordson.com);or
  * telephone on: +001 440-414-5499 (US) and ask for the Nordson data protection officer.

**8\. Recourse, Enforcement and Liability**

Nordson U.S. adheres to the Recourse, Enforcement and Liability Principle, as well as the Verification and Dispute Resolution and Enforcement Supplemental Principles.

Nordson has implemented a self-assessment procedure to verify its adherence to the Principles. If you have a query, concern or complaint about the application of this Privacy Shield Policy or the Processing of EU Personal Data by Nordson U.S., we encourage you to first use the Nordson Contact Details provided in Section 7 above.

Nordson U.S. has further committed to refer unresolved Privacy Shield complaints to JAMS, an alternative dispute resolution provider in the United States. If you do not receive timely acknowledgement of your complaint from us, or if we have not resolved your complaint, please contact or visit JAMS (<http://www.jamsinternational.com/>) for more information or to file a complaint using the complaint submission form found here: <http://www.jamsinternational.com/file-a-privacy-shield-safe-harbor-claim>. The services of JAMS are provided at no cost to you. The JAMS complaint and recourse mechanism described here is available to individuals whose EU Personal Data has been collected or Processed by Nordson under the Principles. The JAMS complaint and recourse mechanism is not available to individuals whose EU Personal Data has been collected or Processed by Nordson under any other EU data transfer adequacy mechanism.

If your complaint is not resolved through Nordson’s internal complaint procedure, or JAMS, you may be able, under certain conditions, to invoke binding arbitration pursuant to Annex I to the Principles. For further information, visit <https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=ANNEX-I-introduction>.

Nordson is also subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission, which has jurisdiction over Nordson U.S.’s compliance with the Privacy Shield.
